<!DOCTYPE components SYSTEM "../FrameworkComponents.dtd">

<panel xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    name="fwAccessControl_EditUser.pnl" fname="fwAccessControl_EditUser" fullname="Edit User panel">
    
    <description> 
    <html:p>
    This panel is used to display and edit the details of the user, and to create new users.
    </html:p>
    The panel has four modes of operation, determined by the access rights and the dollar parameter 
    <html:code>$mode</html:code> (see below): 
    <html:dl>
	<html:dt> <html:em>Edit</html:em> mode</html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 1, allow to edit the details of the user. This mode is active
	if the user has the User Administration access rights, the mode of the panel specified by
	<html:code>$mode</html:code> is not "RO", and non-empty name of the group was passed as the
	<html:code>$groupName</html:code> parameter.
	    <picture id="1" url='fwAccessControl_EditUser.png' caption='Edit User panel in the "edit" mode'/>
	In the edit mode, the <button name="Edit..."/>, <button name="Review"/>, 
	<button name="Show Current Access Rights"/>,
	<button name="Reset"/> ,<button name="OK"/> and <button name="Close"/>buttons are available.
	</html:dd>

	<html:dt> <html:em>Edit own data</html:em> mode </html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 2, allows to modify the full name and description of 
	the own account. This mode is active if a user (not having the User Administration access
	rights) opens the User Edit panel for his own account.
	<picture id="2" url='fwAccessControl_EditUser_own.png' caption='Edit User panel in the "edit own data" mode'/>

	This mode is similar to the <html:em>Edit</html:em> mode. However, only the <html:em>Full name</html:em>,
	and <html:em>Description</html:em> are editable.
	</html:dd>

	<html:dt> <html:em>View</html:em> mode </html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 3, only displays the details of the user and does not allow for changes.
	This mode is active
	if the user has no User Administration access rights and displays the details of other user, 
	or the read-only mode of the panel was requested by setting the
	<html:code>$mode</html:code> to "RO".
	    <picture id="3" url='fwAccessControl_EditUser_view.png' caption='Edit User panel in the "view" mode'/>

	In the view mode, only <button name="Show Current Access Rights"/> and <button name="Close"/>buttons are available.

	</html:dd>

	<html:dt> <html:em>Create</html:em> mode </html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 4, is used to create a new user. This mode is active
	    if the <html:code>$userName</html:code> parameter passed to the panel contained an empty string.
	    <picture id="4" url='fwAccessControl_EditUser_create.png' caption='Edit User panel in the "create" mode'/>
	    
        In the create mode, <button name="Edit..."/>, <button name="Reset"/>, <button name="Create"/>
	and <button name="Close"/>buttons are available.

	</html:dd>	
    </html:dl>
    
    <html:p>
    The panel comprises the following elements:
    <html:ul>
	<html:li>
	<html:em>User name</html:em> text line defines the user name, which identifies the user in a unique way.
	This name is used during the login process and needs to be typed into the
	<otherPanel name="login_panel" text="Login"/> panel.<html:br/>
	Note that the <html:strong>Name_User</html:strong> restriction apply (see the <html:em>Restrictions</html:em> below)
	for user names.
	</html:li>

	<html:li> <html:em>User full name</html:em> text line defines the full name of the user; it is free of restrictions
	concerning the characters used within (i.e. it may contain spaces).<html:br/>
	 Note that the full name is displayed in the
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_UserList" text="User List"/> panel, and the filter therein applies to 
	the user name and the user full name. It is recommended (yet not required) to define non-empty and unique user full name.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li>
	<html:em>Description</html:em> text line contains any additional information - it's meaning is not defined;
	it may be left empty.
	</html:li>

	<html:li>
	<html:em>Password</html:em> text line is used to change user's password (if access rights are sufficient).
	No text is displayed in this field by default. If a new password is typed in, each letter that is typed
	is printed as "*" (asterisk) character. Note that specifying an empty line in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode
	signifies leaving the password as it is, and not specifying the empty password (see also restriction
	<strong>NoEmptyPasswords</strong> in the <html:em>Restrictions</html:em> section below.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li><html:em>id</html:em> text line (not editable) displays the internal unique identifier of the user. It
	is assigned automatically and may not be modified. This field is empty in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode of the panel.
	This idenifier may be of use for the experts and for debugging purposes.
	</html:li>

	<html:li><html:em>Group membership</html:em> table: displays the list of groups to which the user belongs.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="Edit..."/> button: allows to modify (add/remove) the groups to which the user belongs.
	    It brings up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_EditUserGroups" text="Edit User's Group Membership"/> panel;
	    for details refer to the documentation of that panel.
	</html:li>

	<html:li> <button name="Review"/> button: allows to display the changes in user's group membership.
	    It brings up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_ReviewChanges" text="Review Changes"/> panel
	    displaying the changes in group membership
	</html:li>

	<html:li> <button name="Reset"/> button: undoes the changes done in the panel, i.e. in the <html:em>edit</html:em>
	mode resets the contents of all editable fields so that they represent the current settings, while
	in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode it clears alld fields and granted access rights.
	Pressing this button does not apply any settings; it does not close the panel either.
	</html:li>

	
	<html:li> <button name="Show Current Access Rights"/> button: allows to display the list of access rights
	granted currently to the user.
	It brings up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_ShowUserPrivileges" text="User's Access Rights List"/> panel,
	<html:br/>
	Note that the list will not take into account the changes in group membership.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="OK"/> (in <html:em>edit</html:em> mode) or <button name="Create"/>
	    (in <html:em>create</html:em> mode): applies the changes, i.e. modifies or creates the user,
	    and closes the panel.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="Close"/> button: closes the panel without applying the changes.
	</html:li>
	
    </html:ul>    
    </html:p>
    
    </description>

    <instruction action="To create a user">
	Open the panel in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode 
	(e.g. click the <button name="Add"/>
	in the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_UserList" text="User List"/> panel, which
	may be opened using the <button name="Administration>Users"/> context menu of
	the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Toolbar" text="Toolbar"/> panel). <html:br/>
	Fill-in at least the user name
	then press the <button name="Create"/> button.
    </instruction>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <instruction action="To rename a group">
	Make sure the panel is open in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode, for the group you wish to rename;
	type in the modified name into the <html:em>Group name</html:em> text field, 
	then press the <button name="OK"/> button to apply the changes. You may want to alter other 
	settings of the group at the same time, before pressing <button name="OK"/>.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To change the full name or description">
	Make sure the panel is open in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode;
	type in the new full name or description in the appropriate fields,
	then press the <button name="OK"/> button to apply the changes. You may want to alter other 
	settings of the group at the same time, before pressing <button name="OK"/>.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To change the access rights granted to the group">
	Click on the <button name="Edit..."/> button; 
	this will bring up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_EditGroupPrivileges" text="Edit Group's Access Rights"/> panel,
	where you will be able to grant and revoke the access rights; follow the documentation for that panel.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To review the changes in the access rights">
	Click on the <button name="Review"/> button; 
	this will bring up the 
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_ReviewChanges" text="Review Changes"/> panel with lists
	of access rights that are going to be revoked and granted to the group.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To display the list of users belonging to the group">
	Click on the <button name="Show Users"/> button;
	this will bring up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_UsersInGroupList" text="Group Members List"/> panel.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To reset the changes">
	Click on the <button name="Reset"/> button;
	this will fill-in the panel with actual settings for the group (in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode)
	or clear all the fields (in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode).
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To delete a user">
	You need to use the <button name="Delete"/> button in  the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_UserList" text="User List"/>
	panel; it is available, for instance, from the <button name="Administration>Users"/> context menu of the 
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Toolbar" text="Toolbar"/> panel.
    </instruction>    

    <instruction action="To cancel the changes or cancel user creation"> Press the <button name="Close"/> button </instruction>

    <instruction action="To apply the changes made to user"> 
	Press the <button name="OK"/> button; 
	this will bring up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_ConfirmChangeUser" text="Confirm User Change"/> panel,
	asking you for the confirmation of the changes. You will be able to review all the changes, then decide
	to ultimately accept or reject them.
	</instruction>


    <instruction action="To change the password">
	Use the <button name="Change Password"/> option from the context menu of the
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Toolbar" text="Toolbar"/> panel. <html:br/>
	To change other user's password, you need to open the panel in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode,
	then type in the new password in the <html:em>Password</html:em> text field. Note that it is
	not possible to set an empty password this way.
    </instruction>


    <restriction id="Access_User"> To edit an existing user, or create a new user one needs the User Administration
	(or System Administration)
	access rights (see also the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Setup" text="Setup Panel"/>).
	<br/>
	All users are allowed to change the description and the full name of their own account.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="Name_User"> User name must not contain the space ( ), colon (:), semicolon (;), pipe (|), 	
	backslash (\), asterisk (*), apostrophe (') and double-quotes (") characters. 
	User full name and description are, however, free of limitations.<html:br/>
	The user name needs to be unique.
    </restriction>

    <restriction name="NoEmptyPasswords"> Due to security reasons it is not possible to set
    empty password on the existing account.
    If you need to reset the password to an empty one, please contact Access Control expert.
    <html:br/>
    It is, however, possible to create new accounts with empty password. The user will be
    asked to change the password upon the first login.
    </restriction>

    
    <restriction>When the panel is opened as a result of request for group details issued in another
    panel (such as <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_PrivHoldersList" text="Access right holders list"/>),
     a dedicated "User Details" module is opened. This module will be reused to display details of other
    users (i.e. no new windows will be opened for every new inspected user)
    </restriction>

    <dollarParam name="userName"> 
	Specifies the name of the user to edit. Passing an empty string (<html:code>""</html:code>) will open the panel in the 
	<html:em>create</html:em> mode.
    </dollarParam>
    <dollarParam name="mode" scope="optional"> 
	If set to <html:code>"RO"</html:code>, the panel will be opened in the <html:em>view</html:em> mode. 
    </dollarParam>

    <returns> 
	<description> The panel should be opened using functions from the
	    <html:code>ChildPanel...Returns(... , df,ds)</html:code> family. <html:br/>
	    When the panel is closed the following
	    values may be returned in the <html:code>df</html:code> and <html:code>ds</html:code> parameters:
	</description>
	<df idx="1" val="1"> Edit action terminated succesfully, <button name="OK"/> button pressed</df>
	<df idx="1" val="0"> Edit action cancelled, <button name="Close"/> button pressed</df>
	<ds> not used: empty variable is always returned.</ds>
    </returns>
</panel>
