<!DOCTYPE components SYSTEM "../FrameworkComponents.dtd">

<panel xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="fwAccessControl_DomainList.pnl" fname="fwAccessControl_DomainList" fullname="List of domains">
    <description>
	<html:p>
	This panel displays the list of domains defined in the system, and allows to inspect their details,
	modify, create and delete domains (depending on the access rights).
	</html:p>

	<html:p> The panel has two modes of operation: <html:em>edit mode</html:em>, presented in Figure 1,
	 and <html:em>view mode</html:em>, presented in Figure 2.
	<picture id="1" url='fwAccessControl_DomainList.png' caption='The Domain List panel in edit mode'/>
	<picture id="2" url='fwAccessControl_DomainList_view.png' caption='The Domain List panel in view mode'/>
	In the <html:em>view</html:em> mode, only inspection of domains is possible (only <button name="View"/>
	button is available in Figure 2), 
	whereas in the <html:em>edit</html:em>
	mode, it is possible to add, delete and modify domains 
	(<button name="Add"/>,<button name="Delete"/>, <button name="Edit"/> buttons visible on Figure 1).
	</html:p>
	<html:p>
	The mode of operation is determined by the privileges of the user:
	<html:ul>
	    <html:li> if current user has no Domain Administration privilege (see the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Setup" 
	    text="Setup"/> panel), the mode is set to <html:em>view</html:em>. </html:li>
	    
	    <html:li> otherwise, if current user has Domain Administration privilege, the mode is set to <html:em>edit</html:em>. </html:li>
	</html:ul>
	</html:p>
	
	<html:p>
	    The panel allows to filter the names of displayed domains: in Figure 1, the <html:em>Filter</html:em> field is empty, and 
	    all defined domains are displayed in the panel. In Figure 2, however, the <html:em>Filter</html:em> was set
	    to <html:code>*Infrastructure*</html:code>, and only the domains the names (or full names) of which match
	    the expression, are displayed. The <html:em>wildcard character</html:em>, <html:b>*</html:b> (asterisk) may be used
	    in the filter expression to stand for any string of characters.
	    The filter is not case-sensitive, e.g. the <html:code>Abc*</html:code> filter 
	    expression would match names (or full names) such as <html:em>ABC</html:em>, <html:em>aBcDe</html:em>, etc.
	</html:p>
    </description>



    <instruction action="To open this panel">
	Use the <button name="Administration > Domains" type="pressed"/> in the context menu of the
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_CurrentUser" text="Current User"/> object, which is available,
	for instance, in the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Toolbar" text="Toolbar"/> panel.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To view or edit a domain">
	<html:ol>
	<html:li> select a domain in the <html:em>Domains</html:em> list </html:li>
	<html:li> double-click on the selected domain, or click the <button name="Edit"/> or <button name="View"/> button
	(depending on user's privileges).<br/>
	This will bring up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_EditDomain" text="Edit Domain"/> panel,
	in either <html:em>edit</html:em> or <html:em>view</html:em> mode. Follow the instructions for that panel.
	</html:li>
	</html:ol>
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To create a new domain">
	click on <button name="Add"/> button; this will bring up the 
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_EditDomain" text="Edit Domain"/> panel in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode
	of operation; follow the instructions for that panel.
    </instruction>    

    <instruction action="To delete a domain">
	<html:ol>
	<html:li> select a domain in the <html:em>Domains</html:em> list </html:li>
	<html:li> click on <button name="Delete"/> button</html:li>
	<html:li> confirm that you want to delete the domain</html:li>
	</html:ol>
    </instruction>


    <restriction id="Access_UserMgmt"> Domains may be modified, created or deleted (the panel displayed in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode)
	only if the user has Domain Administration (or System Administration) access rights.    
    </restriction>
    
    <restriction id="NoLocalEdit">
	In the Integrated Access Control mode (i.e. with the Access Control Server), the domains may only be modified
	on the machine on which the AC Server is running.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="System_Domain"> It is not possible to delete the system domain.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="UNICOS_Domain"> It is not possible to delete domains in the UNICOS mode of operation.
    </restriction>


</panel>
