<!DOCTYPE components SYSTEM "../FrameworkComponents.dtd">

<panel xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="fwAccessControl_EditDomain.pnl" fname="fwAccessControl_EditDomain" fullname="Edit Domain panel">
    <description> 
    <html:p>
    This panel is used to display and edit the details of the domain, and to create new domains.
    </html:p>
    The panel has three modes of operation, determined by the access rights and the dollar parameter 
    <html:code>$mode</html:code> (see below): 
    <html:dl>
	<html:dt> <html:em>Edit</html:em> mode</html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 1, allow to edit the details of the domain. This mode is active
	if the user has the Domain Administration access rights, the mode of the panel specified by
	<html:code>$mode</html:code> is not "RO", and non-empty name of the domain was passed as the
	<html:code>$domainName</html:code> parameter.
	    <picture id="1" url='fwAccessControl_EditDomain.png' caption='Edit Domain panel in the "edit" mode'/>
	In the edit mode, the <button name="Reset"/>, <button name="Holders..."/>, <button name="OK"/> 
	and <button name="Close"/>buttons are available.
	</html:dd>

	<html:dt> <html:em>View</html:em> mode </html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 2, only displays the details of the domain and does not allow for changes.
	This mode is active
	if the user has no Domain Administration access rights, or the read-only mode of the panel was
	requested by setting the
	<html:code>$mode</html:code> to "RO".
	    <picture id="2" url='fwAccessControl_EditDomain_view.png' caption='Edit Domain panel in the "view" mode'/>

	In the view mode, only <button name="Holders..."/> and <button name="Close"/>buttons are available.

	</html:dd>

	<html:dt> <html:em>Create</html:em> mode </html:dt>
	<html:dd> presented in Figure 3, is used to create a new domain. This mode is active
	    if the <html:code>$domainName</html:code> parameter passed to the panel contained an empty string.
	    <picture id="3" url='fwAccessControl_EditDomain_create.png' caption='Edit Domain panel in the "create" mode'/>
	    
        In the create mode, the <button name="Reset"/>, <button name="Create"/>
	and <button name="Close"/>buttons are available.

	</html:dd>	
    </html:dl>
    
    <html:p>
    The panel comprises the following elements:
    <html:ul>
	<html:li>
	<html:em>Domain name</html:em> text line defines the domain name, which identifies the domain in a unique way.
	Note that the <html:strong>Name_Domain</html:strong> restriction apply (see the <html:em>Restrictions</html:em> below)
	for domain names.
	</html:li>

	<html:li> <html:em>Domain full name</html:em> text line defines the full name of the domain; it is free of restrictions
	concerning the characters used within (i.e. it may contain spaces).<html:br/>
	 Note that the full name is displayed in the
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_DomainList" text="Domain List"/> panel, and the filter therein applies to the domain name and the
	domain full name. It is recommended (yet not required) to define non-empty and unique domain full name.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li>
	<html:em>Description</html:em> text line contains any additional information - it's meaning is not defined;
	it may be left empty.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li><html:em>id</html:em> text line (not editable) displays the internal unique identifier of the domain. It
	is assigned automatically and may not be modified. This field is empty in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode of the panel.
	This idenifier may be of use for the experts and for debugging purposes.
	</html:li>

	<html:li><html:em>Privileges</html:em> table: displays the names of the privileges in the domain. If the panel is open in 
	the <html:em>edit</html:em> or <html:em>create</html:em> mode, privileges' names may be edited directly in the table.
	The numbers left to the names - privilege levels - are the internal identifiers of the privileges;
	they may be of use for experts or debugging; they may not be changed.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="Reset"/> button: undoes the changes done in the panel, i.e. in the <html:em>edit</html:em>
	mode resets the contents of all editable fields so that they represent the current settings, while
	in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode it clears the text fields and sets default privilege names in the table.
	Pressing this button does not apply any settings; it does not close the panel either.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="Holders..."/> button: allows to display the users and groups having certain privileges:
	    it brings up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_PrivHoldersList" text="Privilege Holders List"/> panel,
	    with the domain name preset to the currently edited (inspected) domain, and the privilege name
	    preset to the name of the privilege selected currently in the <html:em>Privileges</html:em> table.<html:br/>
	    Note that this button is disabled until you select a privilege in the <html:em>Privileges</html:em> table.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="OK"/> (in <html:em>edit</html:em> mode) or <button name="Create"/>
	    (in <html:em>create</html:em> mode): applies the changes, i.e. modifies or creates the domain,
	    and closes the panel.
	</html:li>
	
	<html:li> <button name="Close"/> button: closes the panel without applying the changes.
	</html:li>
	
    </html:ul>    
    </html:p>
    
    </description>

    <instruction action="To create a domain">
	Open the panel in the <html:em>create</html:em> mode 
	(e.g. click the <button name="Add"/>
	in the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_DomainList" text="Domain List"/> panel, which
	may be opened using the <button name="Administration>Domains"/> context menu of
	the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Toolbar" text="Toolbar"/> panel). <html:br/>
	Fill-in at least the domain name
	then press the <button name="Create"/> button
    </instruction>
    
    <instruction action="To rename a domain">
	Make sure the panel is open in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode, for the domain you wish to rename;
	type in the modified name into the <html:em>Domain name</html:em> text field, 
	then press the <button name="OK"/> button to apply the changes. You may want to alter other 
	settings of the domain at the same time, before pressing <button name="OK"/>.
    </instruction>


    <instruction action="To change the names of privileges">
	Make sure the panel is open in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode;
	type in the new names of the privileges directly in the
	<html:em>Privileges</html:em> table, 
	then press the <button name="OK"/> button to apply the changes. You may want to alter other 
	settings of the domain at the same time, before pressing <button name="OK"/>.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To change the full name or description">
	Make sure the panel is open in the <html:em>edit</html:em> mode;
	type in the new full name or description in the appropriate fields,
	then press the <button name="OK"/> button to apply the changes. You may want to alter other 
	settings of the domain at the same time, before pressing <button name="OK"/>.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To find a user/group having certain access right">
	Open the panel for the domain in which you want to look for access right,
	click on the privilege name in the <html:em>Privileges</html:em> table,
	then click on the <button name="Holders..."/> button.
	This will bring up the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_PrivHoldersList" text="Privilege Holders List"/> panel;
	follow the instructions for that panel.
    </instruction>

    <instruction action="To delete a domain">
	You need to use the <button name="Delete"/> button in  the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_DomainList" text="Domain List"/>
	panel; it is available, for instance, from the <button name="Administration>Domains"/> context menu of the 
	<otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Toolbar" text="Toolbar"/> panel.
    </instruction>    

    <instruction action="To cancel the changes"> Press the <button name="Close"/> button </instruction>





    <restriction id="Access_Domain"> To edit an existing domain, or create a new domain one needs the Domain Administration
	(or System Administration)
	access rights (see also the <otherPanel name="fwAccessControl_Setup" text="Setup Panel"/>).</restriction>

    <restriction id="Name_Domain"> Domain name must not contain the space ( ), colon (:), semicolon (;), pipe (|), 	
	backslash (\), asterisk (*), apostrophe (') and double-quotes (") characters. 
	The slash (/) parameter is allowed and recommended as logical separator.
	Domain full name and description are, however, free of limitations.<html:br/>
	The domain name needs to be unique.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="Name_Prvilege"> Privilege name must only contain alpanumeric characters (letters, digits).
	 It is recommended that privilege names are single words; if multiple words need to be used to describe the privilege,
	the <html:em>InterCaps</html:em> notation (joining the words while capitalizing the first letters) is recommended,
	even though space character ( ) is allowed in privilege names.
	<html:br/>
	Privilege names <html:em>within the domain</html:em> need to be unique (yet they does not need to be across the domains,
	e.g. there may be <html:code>Control</html:code> privilege in domains <html:code>Domain1</html:code> and 
	<html:code>Domain2</html:code>, resulting in unique access rights <html:em>Domain1:Control</html:em> and
	<html:em>Domain2:Control</html:em> respectively.
    </restriction>
        
    <restriction id="UNICOS_Domain"> In the UNICOS mode of operation, it is not possible to change the full name
    and the description of the domain.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="System_Domain"> The name and full name of the system domain are not allowed. The changes in the
    system domain description will be discarded. The name of the system domain is always equal to the name of the local
    system. The id of the system domain is -1.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="System_Privileges"> The privileges in the system domain reflect the set of 32 PVSS system privileges.
    It is recommended not to change the names of the first five privileges. Privileges from 21 to 32 are reserved for
    the JCOP Framework Access Control - their names should not be changed and they may not be used for own purposes.
    Note that all users will always have privilege level 1 and privileges 21-28 granted.
    </restriction>

    <restriction id="Privilege_Numbers"> Each non-system domain may have up to 8 privileges defined  with id's in
    the range [21,28]). In the UNICOS mode, each domain has 4 privileges.
    </restriction>
    
    
<!-- (this is not used in any panel yet - kept for compatibility with "EditGroup" and "EditUser"
    <restriction>When "browse" mode is active (i.e. displaying domain details requested by doubleclick in other
    panel, a dedicated "Domain Details" module is opened. This module will be reused to display details of other
    domains (i.e. no new windows will be opened for every new inspected domain)</restriction>
-->
    
    <dollarParam name="domainName"> 
	Specifies the name of the domain to edit. Passing an empty string (<html:code>""</html:code>) will open the panel in the 
	<html:em>create</html:em> mode.
    </dollarParam>
    <dollarParam name="mode" scope="optional"> 
	If set to <html:code>"RO"</html:code>, the panel will be opened in the <html:em>view</html:em> mode. 
    </dollarParam>

    <returns> 
	<description> The panel should be opened using functions from the
	    <html:code>ChildPanel...Returns(... , df,ds)</html:code> family. <html:br/>
	    When the panel is closed the following
	    values may be returned in the <html:code>df</html:code> and <html:code>ds</html:code> parameters:
	</description>
	<df idx="1" val="1"> Edit action terminated succesfully, <button name="OK"/> button pressed</df>
	<df idx="1" val="0"> Edit action cancelled, <button name="Close"/> button pressed</df>
	<ds> not used: empty variable is always returned.</ds>
    </returns>
</panel>
